<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<executable>
  <category>TubeTK</category>
  <title>Hybrid Enhancing Anisotropic Diffusion with Continuous Switch (TubeTK)</title>
  <description>Continuous switch between edge enhancing anisotropic diffusion (for homogeneous regions and plate-like structures) and coherence enhancing anisotropic diffusion (for tube-like structures and small spherical structures). Implemented as described in Mendrik et al., Noise reduction in computed tomography scans using 3-D anisotropic diffusion with continuous switch, IEEE Transactions on Medical Imaging, 28(10), pp. 1585-1594, 2009.</description>
  <version>0.1.0.$Revision: 2104 $(alpha)</version>
  <documentation-url>https://public.kitware.com/Wiki/TubeTK</documentation-url>
  <license>Apache 2.0</license>
  <contributor>Danielle F. Pace, Andinet Enquobahrie, Hua Yang, Stephen R. Aylward (Kitware)</contributor>
  <acknowledgements>This work is part of the TubeTK project at Kitware.</acknowledgements>
  <parameters>
    <label>IO</label>
    <description>Input/output parameters.</description>
    <image>
      <name>inputVolume</name>
      <label>Input Volume</label>
      <channel>input</channel>
      <index>0</index>
      <description>Input volume.</description>
    </image>
    <image>
      <name>outputVolume</name>
      <label>Output Volume</label>
      <channel>output</channel>
      <index>1</index>
      <description>Output volume.</description>
    </image>
  </parameters>
  <parameters>
    <label>Filter Parameters</label>
    <double>
      <name>scaleParameter</name>
      <label>Scale</label>
      <description>Scale at which first derivatives are calculated when determining the structure tensor and gradient magnitude. If set too low, filter will be overly sensitive to noise. If set too high, small structures will not be well preserved.</description>
      <longflag>scale</longflag>
      <flag>s</flag>
      <default>1.0</default>
    </double>
    <double>
      <name>eedContrastParameter</name>
      <label>EED Contrast</label>
      <description>Contrast of edges, as opposed to noise (used by the edge enhancing diffusion). If set too low, noise will not be filtered. If set too high, plate-like structures will not be preserved.</description>
      <longflag>EEDContrast</longflag>
      <flag>e</flag>
      <default>20.0</default>
    </double>
    <double>
      <name>cedContrastParameter</name>
      <label>CED Contrast</label>
      <description>Ratio between the second and third eigenvalues that indicates a tube-like structure (used by the coherence enhancing diffusion). If set too low, small spherical structures will not be preserved. If set too high, tubular structures will not be filtered.</description>
      <longflag>CEDContrast</longflag>
      <flag>c</flag>
      <default>30.0</default>
    </double>
    <double>
      <name>alpha</name>
      <label>Alpha</label>
      <description>Regularization parameter to ensure that the diffusion tensor matrix is positive definite and to prevent division by zero (used by both the coherence enhancing diffusion and the continuous switch). Should be set to something very small.</description>
      <longflag>alpha</longflag>
      <flag>a</flag>
      <default>0.001</default>
    </double>
    <double>
      <name>hybridContrastParameter</name>
      <label>Hybrid Contrast</label>
      <description>Contrast of small structures and tubes to be filtered with coherence enhancing diffusion (CED). If set too low, noise in homogeneous regions will look like valid contrast and may be filtered with CED, instead of edge enhancing diffusion (EED). If set too high, only small structures and tubes with high contrast will be filtered with CED, while lower-contrast small structures and tubes will be filtered with EED.</description>
      <longflag>hybridContrast</longflag>
      <flag>y</flag>
      <default>30.0</default>
    </double>
    <double>
      <name>timeStep</name>
      <label>Time Step</label>
      <description>Time step used in optimization.</description>
      <longflag>timeStep</longflag>
      <flag>t</flag>
      <default>0.11</default>
    </double>
    <integer>
      <name>numberOfIterations</name>
      <label>Number of Iterations</label>
      <description>Number of iterations used in optimization.</description>
      <longflag>numIterations</longflag>
      <flag>n</flag>
      <default>1</default>
    </integer>
  </parameters>
</executable>
